here at the 2026 uh NFL scouting combine
and joined by Drew Petting, the new
offensive coordinator for the Detroit
Lions. Drew, thanks for taking a few
minutes here.
>> Yeah, Tim, thanks for having me.
>> All right, let's let's start with this.
You know, we talked to Dan Campbell
earlier and he said within 20 minutes of
interviewing you and and he interviewed,
you know, maybe close to a dozen guys
for the offensive coordinator job. He
said he I knew Drew was the guy within
20 minutes when you sat down and you
guys started talking about offensive
football. What was it that just seemed
to click? Why why was this a great fit
for you?
>> Yeah, for me it was, you know, so many
different reasons. From a philosophy
standpoint, from a culture standpoint,
from a roster standpoint that they've
done just such a good job of building
the foundation of this team, uh, in
terms of their belief in what it takes
to win football games. It was just a
great opportunity for me and, you know,
I'd like to think that my belief in
terms of how games should be won, how
you should play the game, you know,
offensive scheme and how you interact
with people on a regular basis showed
through. Uh, and I just think it it felt
natural right from the get-go. What does
the best version of of Drew Petting's
offense look like on the field on game
day? And and it might be different week
to week. I
>> I think ultimately the best version of
any offense is going to be built around
the players. I think that's so critical
to to the success we want to have on
offense in any building. And you know,
here in Detroit, they have so many core
players that have played the game at
such a high level that if we're doing
things the way we need to, those guys
are affecting the game week in and week
out and allowing us to put up one more
point than the other team. when you sat
down and started looking at the cutups
and just preparing, you know, the
players that you were going to inherit,
do you start to pinch yourself at all
with a top five running back, a top five
tight end, a top five wide receiver, a
top five right tack, you can stop me
anytime, no top corner, you know what
I'm saying? I mean, just when you
started to look at it, how excited are
you about that aspect of it that you've
got so many different weapons that you
can move around, play a lot of different
versions of your offense, it seems like
w with just the skilled guys that you
have. Yeah, I think you hit it on. It
was one of those things, you know, I
think when from a distance when you're
on, you know, you're on a different
team, you see it, you hear about it, you
appreciate and respect it, and then
going into the interview and starting to
dive down into the tape and watching a
little bit more about what these guys
really do and how they played down in
and down out. Uh, it was uh, you know,
it was a no-brainer. Just so impressive
the type of production they've had from
so many different positions here over
the last couple years. And it speaks to
to the culture that Dan's built and the
system that they've built here and then
what Brad's been able to do from a
roster standpoint. just really
impressive.
>> Creativity, versatility. How important
are those two words in in in kind of
offensive football? What you're about?
>> Yeah, I think they're I think those are
what the league is about. You know, if
you have to go to the same well every
time to win games or produce points, you
know, we're at a point in the NFL where
defenses are going to pick up on that.
They're going to find ways to take it
away and force you to do something else.
And I think that creativity and that
that flexibility to adapt and be who you
need to be when you want to be that is
so important to winning football games.
Jared Goff. I know you've had
conversations with him as you guys kind
of start to to to build this thing up.
Just what have those conversations been
like and and how much are you looking
forward to working with a guy like Jared
Drew? A guy who's been in this league
for 10 years, has seen everything.
There's nothing a defense is going to
throw at him that he hasn't seen. So,
just being able to work with him, how
much are you looking forward to that?
>> Uh, tremendously. And I think that
showed through from the very first time
I talked to him. Just his his passion
for the sport, his work ethic, the way
he thinks about the game, uh, shows
through in in everything he does. you
know, on top of that being a great guy,
someone you're going to want to be
around and go to work with every day.
Uh, but really just impressed with his,
you know, as you said, the knowledge of
the game, the experience that he can
pull from, and really his work ethic and
the and the way he goes about his job
has been really impressive.
>> Probably the best running back tandem in
in the league in Detroit and Jamir Gibbs
and David Montgomery. Just what's your
vision for for how you see those guys
fitting in your offense and and what you
can do with those two guys?
>> Yeah, I think to the earlier
conversation we were having, you know,
those two are very dynamic players. you
know, they do a lot of different things
well and they put a ton of stress on the
defense. So, being able to utilize both
those in any capacity is going to be
huge for our success. And I think you've
seen that throughout their tenure here
in Detroit.
>> The wide receiver core, we talk about
versatility and and there's versatility
within within position groups, too. I
mean, you look at that rope in Detroit,
you've got a top five speed guy in um in
J Mo. You've got a possession guy, one
of the leading receivers in the league
in in St. Brown, and then an upandcomer,
big size, big catch radius in in Tesla.
What do you like about that group and
the versatility that you have to maybe
do a lot of different things within that
group?
>> Yeah, I think the versatility is a a
part of it, but I think one of the other
things that's impressive about that
group is really all three of those guys
and some other guys in those room can do
just about anything you ask them to do.
I think that's when you start being
really dynamic. It's yeah, this guy can
take the top off or this guy can play
underneath, but knowing that they can
all do a little bit of that, we're not
necessarily predictable in the roles we
put them or how we move them around the
formation. I think that is really what
makes you hard to defend. You know, you
ran a lot of 12 personnel in in in
Arizona, a lot of 13 personnel. Some of
that was because of the injuries and
just the the situation, but how much do
you see that being able to be something
that you can use here too with the the
wide or the the tight end group that
you're inheriting, the offensive line
and and just some of the pieces that you
have?
>> Yeah, I think changing personnels to,
you know, to the earlier point of trying
to stay flexible and adaptable as we go
throughout the season, it puts stress on
the defense cuz, you know, we can line
up in 12 and be in 11 sets. We can be in
11 and line up in 12 sets. You can get
into 13 and move people around the
formation and kind of get into some
different looks. And I think the more
you can do that, the harder it is for a
defense to kind of lock in on who you
are and what you're trying to do, which
ultimately is going to make you harder
to defend.
>> How important is it to get this
offensive lineback playing to where it
was in 2023, 2024. I know that's before
you got here, but they were more of the
middle of of the pack last year. Getting
that unit back to being dominant. How
important is that to to being able to
run the kind of offense that you run and
how do you go about doing that? I I
think the offensive line all, you know,
regardless of what offense you want to
run, is probably the key piece of any
offense. You know, everything you do,
every time you snap the ball, those five
guys have to be in unison. They have to
be playing at a high level if you're
going to do any run game, pass game,
screen game, you name it, those guys are
heavily involved in it. So, I think
that's always going to be a focal point.
Um, and there's an attitude piece that
goes with that and the way that we want
to play the game and the type of
physicality that we want to play the
game with. So, you know, from, you know,
Hank on down, from, you know, the little
details of coaching stuff the right way,
from the way that we organize the scheme
to the type of players we bring in, I
think so much of that, uh, has to be,
you know, really focused on throughout
the offseason and going into training
camp.
>> I'm glad you mentioned Hank. I want you
to just talk on your offensive staff a
little bit. You know, Mike Cafky, I got
a history there. Just what's your
overall impression of of that staff? I
know you've been close with a with a
number of those guys. How much you
looking forward to kind of just just
starting the grind with with those with
those guys on your offensive staff?
Yeah, the staff has been amazing. You
you know, I had a prior relationship
with Hank, which, you know, was special
to get back with him and and kind of
pick up where we left off when we we got
went our separate ways there in
Minnesota. But you look at all those
guys. I'm not going to name them all by
name. We could be here for a little
while, especially we started going
through their resumes because they're
impressive coaches who have been in some
really impressive spots who, you know,
who bring a lot of knowledge and a lot
of personality to the offense and are
going to have a big part on who we
become. I think that's really what kind
of makes it exciting for me is getting
them all in the room, getting those
ideas together, making sure it fits, and
trying to be the best version of the
Detroit Lions. You know, the new league
year starts next month, the start of
free agency, but then it's a draft and
I'd be a little remiss if I didn't ask
you about the combine and and we're
here. What's your favorite part of of of
this week in the combine? How much do
you guys as a staff get out of this
week? I
>> I think one of the best parts about this
week is it's really our first
opportunity to get around some of the
players. You know, you watch them on
tape, you hear their names, you you see
some of the list, but now it's a chance
to interact with them a little bit, see
what makes them tick, see what their
knowledge of the game is like, see, you
know, to that point about Jared loving
the game. And really, you can feel that
the second you talk to them. You know,
you want to feel that from some of these
guys and you want to see what they're
like on a daily basis. And you know,
it's their first interview for a job,
which is always kind of exciting to see
how they handle that stress and that
pressure. Uh because that's a big part
of what this league is.
>> The tape is obviously the ultimate, you
know, reason you get into the NFL. But
you love those interview. You love that
interview part of it. Is that the key
part here? What
>> I do? Absolutely. I mean, unless we're
going to put pads on and play football,
I think that's probably the second best
thing we can do is just get around these
guys and really start to get to know
Well, I know Lions fans are excited to
see what you have in store for the
offense. Drew, thanks so much for taking
a few moments. Appreciate it.
>> Appreciate it, Tim.